A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Education and Research Division (E&R), Program Files FA633
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Education and Research Division (E&R), Program Files
1954-1981 (Bulk: 1963-1980)
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA633
61 Box(es)
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Travel Study Awards, 1967-1976; I
  - Travel and Study Awards 699-0017, 1967-1970
    - Alfaro, Dr. Angel Q. Quintero, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Wilton, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Atkin, J. Myron, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Banks, John A.G., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Beberman, Max, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Bereday, George Z.F., 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Chen, Ai Yen, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Dethier, Gaston, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - Ferrara, Elda, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Fish, Kenneth, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Griffiths, Dr. Daniel E., 1970 (Box 1)
    - Kernan, Claudia Mitchell, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Kogan, Maurice, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Laister, Bryan, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Miller, Blanche L., 1969 (Box 1)
    - Mittler, Carl Heinz, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Nash, Samuel, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Portzek, Hans, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Rothenberg, Myra, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Seow, Paul, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Sherburne, Mary Leila, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Sinclair, John McHardy, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
    - Twyman, Charles R., 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Van Wely, Hendrik Albert, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Wight, James, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Travel and Study Awards 700-00-193/709-0003-320/699-0017, 1969-1974
    - Bingham, Margaret, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Cook, Jenny, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
    - Derrick, June, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    - Eckstein, Max A., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Elliott, John, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Getzels, J.W., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Gilliard, June V., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Hernandez, Edward M., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Hernandez, Edward M., 1973 (Box 2)
    - Hipkin, John, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Jarolimek, John, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Lively, John J., 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - MacDonald, Barry, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Moreland, Olvin, Jr., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Noah, Harold J., 1970 (Box 2)
    - Reimer, Everett W., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Reimer, Everett W. (Attachment Folder), 1974 (Box 2)
    - Ruddock, Jean, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Smith, Lee H., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Stenhouse, Lawrence, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Walker, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Wilderson, Dr. Frank B., Jr., 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Travel and Study Awards 709-0003-320, 1970-1976
    - Berke, Joel S., 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - Berke, Joel S. -- Attachment File, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Carter, James A., 1975 (Box 3)
    - Chittenden, Edward A., 1971 (Box 3)
    - Chittenden, Edward A. -- Attachment File, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Coons, John E., 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Coons, John E., n.d. (Box 3)
    - Darnell, Frank, 1973-1975 (Box 3)
    - Darnell, Frank -- Attachment File, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
    - Husen, Torston, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - James, Charity, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - James, Charity -- Attachment File, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Jones, Joan, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Lawrence, Charles R., III, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - Melser, John, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Miner, Jerry, 1970-1975 (Box 3)
    - Monroe, Vivian, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - Pettet, Ann E., 1971-1976 (Box 3)
    - Robinson, James E., 1972 (Box 3)
    - Stone, Joseph, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Sturges, A.W., 1971 (Box 3)
    - Willis, William M., 1972-1976 (Box 3)
  - Travel and Study Awards 729-0003-320, 1967-1975
    - Allen, Mildred, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
    - Appleby, Monica K., 1972-1974 (Box 4)
    - Appleby, Monica K. -- Attachment File, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Brownstein, Bonnie, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
    - Davis, John B., 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Evans, Ronald, 1971-1974 (Box 4)
    - Evans, Ronald -- Attachment File, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Gang, Seymour, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Goodman, Dorothy B., 1972 (Box 4)
    - Hein, George H., 1972-1974 (Box 4)
    - Leary, William J., 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - MacDonald, Barry, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Maxwell, Marcella, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Marcella, Maxwell -- Attachment File, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Nickens, Norman W., 1973 (Box 4)
    - Nickens, Norman W. -- Attachment File, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Norris, Martha A., 1971-1975 (Box 4)
    - Sandler, Jerrold, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Sandler, Jerrold -- Attachment File, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Shafer, Susanne M., 1972-1974 (Box 4)
    - Shafer, Susanne M. -- Attachment File, 1974 (Box 4)
    - Steinberger, David, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - Vesenyi, Paul, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Vroom, Victor H., 1967 (Box 4)
    - Watanabe, Yasuo, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Weinstein, Paul, 1967 (Box 4)
- Doctoral Fellowships for Black Americans, 1969-1972; II
  - Adams, Betty Livingston, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Allen, Ted Wayne, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Bonner, Andrew Fritz, Jr., 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Bostic, James Edward, Jr., 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Clemens, Marc Daryl, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Crutcher, Ronald A., 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Davis, Dwight, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Eure, Herman E., 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Linda Boone, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Fisher, Nona Ruth, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Gay, Phillip Timothy, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Gray, Jerome Armstead, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Greene, Rosanne, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Greenway, Clarence David, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Harris, Timothy R., 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Harris, William Stacy, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Hopkins, Peggy, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Byron Gentry, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Raymond Edward, 1969-1971 (Box 5)
- Black and Mexican Advanced Study Fellows 719-0022, 1971-1972; III
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, A-Ch 719-0022, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, Cl-E 719-0022, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, F-G 719-0022, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, H 719-0022, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, J-Mi 719-0022, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, Mo-Sp, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, St-V, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows, W-Wy, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Mexican-American Advanced Study Fellows, A-Z (1/2), 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Mexican-American Advanced Study Fellows, A-Z (2/2), 1971-1972 (Box 7)
- Doctoral Awards for Black Americans, 1969-1970; IV
  - Jones, Enrico Edison, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Jordan, William Chester, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - McNeil, Genna Rae, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Morrison, Cheryl Elaine, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Pemberton, Gayle Renee, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Payne, Charles M., 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Myers, Harvey Nathaniel, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Moorman, Edward Lewis, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Porter, Henry Lee, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Smith, Andetrie Dolores, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Smith, Michael David, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Snedecor, Dan Vernon, Jr., 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Waddell, Edward W., Jr., 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Wallace, Rudolph Waldron, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Ward, Alice, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Wardlaw, Alvia Jean, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Williams, Archie Lee, Jr., 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Williams, John Raymond, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
- Black Doctoral Fellows, 1971-1972; V
  - Doctoral -- Black Complete, J-Mc, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Doctoral -- Black Complete, M-P, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Doctoral -- Black Complete, Q-S, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
- Advanced Study Awards for Native Americans, Puerto Ricans, Black Americans, and Mexican Americans, 1971-1973; VI
  - Puerto Rican Advanced Study Fellows, A-Z 719-0022/21, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - American Indian Advanced Study Fellows, A-Z 719-0022/21, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
  - Collins, Tamara, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Henley, Laura Arlene, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Jackson, Gwendolyn, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Milner, Charles Edward, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Vassall, John Henry II, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Witt, Clarence Eugene, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Budlong, Donalda Lee, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Candelario, Angelo Ortega, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Coleman, Raquel Zaragoza, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Dimas, Pete Ray, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Hermosillo, Connie, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Gonzalez, Stephen Moore, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Gutierrez, Ronald Steven, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Saenz, Richard, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Kayotawape, James D., 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Loera, Orlando Jose, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Magana, Maria Lou, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Holappa, Theodore Reuben, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Malave, Myrna Luz, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Maldonado, Martin Froilan, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Marrero, Antonio Lopez, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Norman, Norma-Andrea Martinez, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Oliver, Arthur Thomas, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Ontiveros, Jay T., 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Peters, Christopher Herman, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Ritchey, Carol Ann, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Rivera, George Luis, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Robles, Guadalupe, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Strong (Wells), Karen Roberts, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Talavera, Ralph, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Torres, Lureida M., 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - White (Deane), Denise Marie, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
- Black Advanced Study Fellows, 1972-1973; VII
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- A-Bo, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- Brewer-Cu, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- D-Fr, 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- K-M, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- Mc-O, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- P-R, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- S, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- T-Wh, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- Williams, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Black Advanced Study Fellows -- Williams-Z, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
- Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans, 1972-1973; VIII
  - Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans -- A-Co, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans -- Cr-Du, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans -- E-H, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans -- I-Li, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Advanced Study Fellowships -- American Indians, Mexican Americans, Puerto Ricans -- Lo-Mu, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
- Black American Advanced Study Fellows, 1970-1971, 1972-1973; IX
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- A-Cox, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- Craig-H, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- J-L, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- G, 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- H (1/2), 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- H (2/2), 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- I-J, 1972-1973 (Box 16)
- Black Administrative Officers, 1968-1973; X (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- A-Z, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Aldrich, Bobby Eugene, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Armstead, William Sim, III, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Austin, Frank Edward, Jr., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Bingham, Haskell S., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Bryan, Barbara Hunt, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Clarke, Velma Greene, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Frasier, Mary Mack, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Howard, Leon, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Jenkins, Celia Hudson, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Jordan, Mary Finley, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Marshall, Nexton Phillip, Jr., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Overby, Sandra Jones, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Parker, Larnell R., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Ratchford, Jerome, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Richard, Alvin J., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Richardson, Earl Stanford, 1972-1973 (Box 17)
  - Black Administrative Officers -- Advanced Study Fellows -- Settle, Joseph C., 1972-1973 (Box 17)
- Peter Fraenkel Files, 1962-1969; XI
  - Personal Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 18)
  - Program Budget FY 1969, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
  - Tingo Maria and Pucallpa, 1968 (Box 18)
  - CADE, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Seminar Meeting of Latin American Program Advisors, Colombia, 1968 (Box 18)
  - General Planning Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 18)
  - Sociology -- San Marcos, 1963 (Box 18)
  - San Marcos University -- Administrative Services, 1963-1966 (Box 18)
  - Agrarian University -- Basic Sciences, 1964 (Box 18)
  - Basic Sciences -- San Marcos, 1964 (Box 18)
  - General Studies -- San Marcos, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - National Engineering University, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Catholic University, 1963-1969 (Box 18)
- Special Projects, 1957-1974; XII
  - Year-Round Education, 1974 (Box 20)
  - SPE News Releases, 1961-1962 (Box 20)
  - SP -- Journalism Releases, Apr 1965-Aug 1967 (Box 20)
  - Liberal Education in the University -- Program Planning Budget, Apr 1966 (Box 20)
  - Undergraduate Education -- SP Budget, Jun 1965 (Box 20)
  - Ford Foundation FCC Filings Re: Domestic Non-Common Carrier Communication Satellite Facilities by Non-Governmental Entities, 1966-1967 (Box 20)
  - A National Non-Commerical Television Service -- Report and Recommendations, Mar 1963 (Box 20)
  - A National Non-Commerical Television Service -- Report and Recommendations, Jun 1963 (Box 20)
  - Proposed Financial Support Program for Educational Television Stations, Mar 1965 (Box 20)
  - Regional ETV Production Centers, Jun 1966 (Box 20)
  - A Report on Journalism Education, Jun 1963 (Box 20)
  - Special Program in Education -- Discussion Paper, Sep 1963 (Box 20)
  - Special Projects -- Educational Television (Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction), 1963-1968; XII.1
    - Final Recommendations Concerning the National Program for the Use of Television in the Schools and Related Projects, Sep 1963 (Box 19)
    - A Note on the National Program, Sep 1963 (Box 19)
    - Exhibit 1 -- Supporting Comments of Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Apr 1964 (Box 19)
    - Exhibit 2 -- Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Inc. -- Engineering Portion of Comments, Apr 1964 (Box 19)
    - Reply Comments of Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Inc., 1964 (Box 19)
    - Comments of Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Inc., Apr 1964 (Box 19)
    - Member Schools of the Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
    - The Hidden Medium: Educational Radio -- A Status Report, Apr 1967 (Box 19)
    - A Review of the Special Program of Capital Grants to Universities and Colleges, [1968] (Box 19)
    - Dimensions of Recent Growth in Private Universities and Colleges, Sep 1968 (Box 19)
    - Midwest Program on Airborne Television Instruction, Inc., 1966 (Box 19)
    - FCC Filings, 1966-1967 (Box 19)
  - Special Projects -- Educational Television, 1957-1969; XII.2
    - Television in Schools -- Ford Foundation, 1958-1962 (Box 21)
    - Television in Schools -- Ford Foundation -- Attachment File, 1958-1962 (Box 21)
    - National Program in the Use of Television in the Public Schools -- Visitation Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 21)
    - New Jersey Public Broadcasting -- Miscellaneous Correspondence, Memoranda and Notes Re: ETV, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - New Jersey Public Broadcasting -- New Jersey Governor's Commission on Public Broadcasting -- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
    - New Jersey Public Broadcasting -- Current Correspondence, 1968 (Box 21)
    - New Jersey Public Broadcasting -- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 21)
    - New Jersey Commission on Public Broadcasting -- Papers, Memoranda, Reports, etc., 1967-1968 (Box 21)
- Fellowships and Reports, 1967-1978; XIII
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- M-S, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Black American Advanced Study Fellows -- T-Z, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Mexican-American and Puerto Rican Advanced Study Fellows -- A-Z, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - American Indian Advanced Study Fellows -- A-Z, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Reports on 1974-1975 Fellowships -- ETS, NFF (Refunds), 1976-1977 (Box 22)
  - Graduate Fellowships for Black Americans -- NFF, 1974-1977 (Box 22)
  - Black Advanced Study, 1970-1971 (Box 22)
  - Doctoral Fellowships, 1971 (Box 22)
  - Doctoral Fellowships, 1972-1973 (Box 22)
  - Minority DAPs, 1967-1978 (Box 22)
- Mario Fantino Files, 1952-1970; XIV
  - Mario Fantini Correspondence Files, 1967-1970; XIV.1 (Box 23)
    - Alphabetical Correspondence Files, A-Z (25 folders), 1967-1970 (Box 23)
    - Pending, 1970 (Box 23)
    - To Be Done, 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Feb 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Mar 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, May 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Oct 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Nov 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Dec 1969 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jan 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Feb 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Mar 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Apr 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, May 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jun 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Jul 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Aug 1970 (Box 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, Sep 1970 (Box 23)
  - Mario Fantini Subject Files, 1952-1970; XIV.2
    - Urban Teacher Preparation Program, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Syracuse Board of Education, 1964-1966 (Box 24)
    - AACTE -- Institute for Study of Disadvantaged, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Basil Bernstein's Papers, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Bilingual Children, 1965 (Box 24)
    - England, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Englewood, New Jersey Public Schools, 1965-1966 (Box 24)
    - Integration -- Desegregation, 1966 (Box 24)
    - Negro Education, 1965 (Box 24)
    - Materials for Neiman Fellows Meeting -- General, Feb 23, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Materials for Neiman Fellows Meeting -- Book Chapter I -- Who are the Disadvantaged, Feb 23, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Materials for Neiman Fellows Meeting -- Who are the Disadvantaged, Feb 23, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Strategies for Change -- Working File, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Organizing for Diversity, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Education -- Ford Foundation School Improvement Workshop, 1966 (Box 25)
    - Elementary School Teaching Project -- Raw Materials, 1964-1965 (Box 25)
    - Elementary School Teaching Project -- General, 1964-1967 (Box 25)
    - Elementary School Teaching Project -- Reports of Visits, 1965 (Box 25)
    - Elementary School Teaching Project -- Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 25)
    - Fantini/Weinstein Papers, n.d. (Box 25)
    - Integration, 1965-1966 (Box 25)
    - Book -- Correspondence and General, 1965 (Box 25)
    - Public Schools of Choice, undated (Box 26)
    - European Trip, Jul 19-Sep 8, 1969 (Box 26)
    - President's National Advisory Council, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Guttentag, Marcia -- Project on Effects of Decentralization, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Urban Education -- Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Urban Education -- Filing, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Urban Education -- Public and Non-Public School Options, 1970 (Box 26)
    - Conference on Graduate Education, Dec 20-21, 1952 (Box 26)
    - Early Admissions, 1956 (Box 26)
    - Educational TV and Radio Center -- Publications, 1960-1966 (Box 26)
    - The Fund for the Advancement of Education -- Conference on Professional Education, Jan 22-23, 1953 (Box 26)
    - Conference on Inequalities of Educational Opportunity, Jan 3-4, 1953 (Box 26)
    - Armed Forces Education Program -- Committee Meeting, Jan 27, 1953 (Box 26)
    - The Reports on the College Teacher Internship Programs, 1953-1954, Oct 1954 (Box 26)
    - Palo Alto Conference, Aug 1955 (Box 26)
    - Conference on College Self-Studies, 1953 (Box 26)
    - Conference on College Self-Studies, 1954 (Box 26)
    - Douglas Porter Report -- Audio Visual Aids in Foreign Language Teaching, 1958 (Box 26)
    - PS 1 -- Manhattan, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Leads on School Visits, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Observations to be Typed, n.d. (Box 27)
    - LSP Notes on Reading, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Fantini Visits, 1964 (Box 27)
    - EST Project -- Weekly Reports, 1965 (Box 27)
    - E.S.T.P. Observations, 1964 (Box 27)
    - California Schools, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Colorado Schools, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Florida Schools, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Florida Universities, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Georgia Public Schools, 1963 (Box 27)
    - Illinois Universities, 1964 (Box 27)
    - New Orleans Schools, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Baltimore Schools, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Syracuse, NY, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Madison Area Project -- Syracuse, NY, 1964 (Box 27)
    - Raleigh, NC, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Schools -- Pennsylvania, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Washington, DC, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Answers to Original ESTP Letter, 1964-1965 (Box 27)
    - Ford Foundation -- General, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Foundation and Federal Programs (Box 27)
    - General Correspondence -- Outgoing, 1965 (Box 27)
    - General Notes -- ESTP, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Inter-Office Memoranda, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Progress Report -- EST Project, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Reports, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Two Year Colleges, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Staff Discussion Papers and Reports, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Leads for School Visits, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Migrant Children, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Englewood, NJ, 1965 (Box 27)
    - Schools -- New Haven, CT, 1964 (Box 27)
    - E.S.T.P., 1965 (Box 27)